没错　你也听到了　贱货
That's right. You heard me, bitch.
有问题吗
You got a problem?
够爷们的话就放马过来
Bring it on if you're man enough,
不然的话就乖乖认命
or take it up the chain if you're a pussy.
你也听到了
You heard me,
你个娘炮婊子士官
You pussy-ass noncom bitch.
你又不聋
You ain't deaf.
去你妈的服从命令听指挥
Take it up the damn chain of command.
你他妈给老子见鬼去吧
or you can kiss my lily-white ass.
没错
That's right.
我就这么说了　你听得一清二楚
That's what I said. You heard me.
之后这个白痴　他挥了一拳
And then this idiot, he takes a swing,
告诉你…
You know, and well…
你真该欣赏下他的表情
Oh, you should've seen the look on his face.
我把他门牙都打掉了
When I punched out his front teeth.
五颗门牙
Yeah, five of 'em.
乒乒乓乓　就像这样
Pow! Pow! Just like that.
我的天
Oh my god.
这么一来害得我
16 months in the stockade…
蹲了16个月监狱
Oh, that's what them teeth cost me.
那时真是
That was…
真是难熬啊
That was hard time,
但说实话　光是看着
But by god, it was worth every minute of it.
那混球把自己的牙
Just to see that prick.
吐在地上　真他妈的绝对值了
Spit his teeth out on the ground.
是的　长官
Yes sir,
绝对值
Worth every minute.
不
Oh no.
不不不
No no! No no! No no!
老天爷
God! Godod.
不要
No no!
耶稣基督
God! Jesus!
不不　仁慈的上帝
No no, merciful christ!
不要
No no. No no.
上帝啊　救救我
God, help me! God! God!
老天爷啊　行行好
Jesus, please! Jesus, please.
救我　快救救我
Help me! Come on now!
救命
Help me.
不要
No no. Oh, no no.
老天爷
Oh my god.
天啊　上帝啊
No, jesus. Jesus.
不要
No no no no no no.
求你了
Please.
我这人太坏　我知道
I didn't behave, I know.
我是罪有应得
I know I'm being punished.
我知道
I know. I…
我活该　我活该
Oh, I deserve it. I deserve it.
我一直很坏
I've been bad.
求你现在帮帮我　给我一条出路
Help me now. Show me the way.
求你了　救救我
Go on, tell me what to do.
快告诉我怎么办
Tell me. Tell me.
老天爷
God!
好吧
That's okay.
不用在意了　你个白痴耶稣
Never you mind, silly christ boy.
我之前没求过你
I ain't begged you before.
现在也别指望我求你
I ain't gonna start begging now.
我死也不要求你
I ain't gonna beg you now!
你不用操心了
Don't you worry about me.
我再也不会求你了
Begging you ever! I'll never beg you!
我死也不会求你
I ain't gonna beg you!
我之前从没求过你
I never begged you before.
不
No!
《行尸走肉》
你别放在心上了
Best not to dwell on it.
莫尔被一个人扔在那儿
Merle got left behind.
他回不来没人会难过
Nobody's gonna be sad he didn't come back…
好吧　也许除了达里尔
Except maybe Daryl.
- 达里尔是谁　-他弟弟
- Daryl? - His brother.
至少有人今天过得很开心
At least somebody's having a good day.
- 还给我　-住手
- Give it back. - Stop it.
- 不要　-是我找到的
- No! - I found it.
- 不要　-给我
- No! - Give it.
米约　别和你姐姐吵了
Mijo, leave your sister alone.
- 为什么　-听话
- Why? - Come on.
亲爱的　你越烦躁就得越久
Baby, the more you fidget, the longer it takes.
- 别动了　好吗　-我尽力了
- So don't, okay? - I'm trying.
那就再尽力点
Well, try harder.
你这样就受不了的话
If you think this is bad,
等到刮胡子时有你好受
wait till you start shaving.
那可痛呢
That stings.
等到那时
That day comes, you'll be.
你会无比怀念妈妈给你理发
wishing for one of your mama's haircuts.
真这么夸张　我才不信
I'll believe that when I see it.
这样吧　如果你像个男子汉那样
I'll tell you what… you just get through this.
好好理发
with some manly dignity and.
明天我教你点特别的玩意
tomorrow I'll teach you something special.
我教你怎么抓青蛙
I will teach you to catch frogs.
- 我以前抓过青蛙　-我是说一群青蛙
- I've caught a frog before. - I said frogs… plural.
小家伙　那是门艺术　抓起来可不容易
And it is an art, my friend. It is not to be taken lightly.
其中的方法和工具
There are ways and means.
知道的人寥寥无几
Few people know about it.
而我愿意告诉你这秘诀
I'm willing to share my secrets.
我是女生　你和他说
Oh, I'm a girl. You talk to him.
仅此一次　不得反悔哦
It's a one-time offer, bud… not to be repeated.
我们干嘛要这么多青蛙
Why do we need frogs, plural?
- 你没吃过青蛙腿吗　-好恶
- You ever eat frog legs? - Eww!
- 不　很美味　-他说得对　很恶
- No, yum! - No, he's right. Eww.
当你吃够了那些罐头豆子
When you get down to that last can of beans,
肯定会爱死青蛙腿的　女士
You're gonna be loving those frog legs, lady.
我现在就能猜到你说　肖恩
I can see it now… "Shane,
你看能再多给我一份吗
Do you think I could have a second helping, please?
- 拜托　就一份　-是吗　走着瞧
- Please? Just one? - Yeah, I doubt that.
别听她的　小伙子
Don't listen to her, man.
咱俩是英雄　我们会给那帮人
You and me, we'll be heroes. We'll feed these folks.
搞到法式田鸡腿大餐
Cajun-style kermit legs.
我宁愿吃猪肉
I would rather eat miss piggy.
不过也好吃不到哪去
Yes, that came out wrong.
孩子　数英雄人物
Heroes, son, spoken of in song and legend.
还看你我　肖恩和卡尔
You and me, Shane and Carl.
戴尔　你那里什么情况
Hey, Dale, can you see what that is?
怎么了　戴尔
Talk to me, Dale!
还不好说
I can't tell yet.
是他们吗　他们回来了吗
Is it them? Are they back?
我勒个去
I'll be damned.
- 什么东西　-我猜是被盗车辆
- What is it? - A stolen car is my guess.
- 靠　把那破报警器关了　-我关不了
- Holy crap. Turn that damn thing off! - I don't know how!
把车前盖打开　听到没有啊
Pop the hood, please. Pop the damn hood,
我姐安德莉亚…
My sister Andrea…
- 打开前盖　-什么　行行　好了好了
- Pop the damn hood! - What? Okay okay. Yeah yeah yeah.
- 可以了　-她好吗　她没事吧
- Yeah yeah! - Is she okay? Is she all right?
- 没事　她没事　-她回来了吗
- She's okay! She's okay! - Is she coming back?
- 是的　-那她怎么没和你在一起
- Yes! - Why isn't she with you?
- 她在哪儿　真没事吗　-真没事
- Where is she? She's okay? - Yes!
都没事　大家都没事
Yeah, fine. Everybody is.
除了倒霉的莫尔
Well, Merle not so much.
你疯啦　开辆鬼哭狼嚎的破车回来
Are you crazy, driving this wailing bastard up here?
非要把那堆臭僵尸都引过来吗
Are you trying to draw every walker for miles?
- 放心没事　-这他妈还叫没事啊
- I think we're okay. - You call being stupid okay?
警报器的声音会在山谷里回响
Well, the alarm was echoing all over these hills.
根本辨别不出位置
Hard to pinpoint the source.
我不是抬杠　也就说说
I'm not arguing. I'm just saying.
下次你不能长点脑子吗
It wouldn't hurt you to think things through.
又不会缺胳膊短腿　行吗
a little more carefully next time, would it?
对不起
Sorry.
好歹算弄了台靓车
Got a cool car.
下来见见大家
Come meet everybody.
- 艾米　-安德莉亚
- Amy. - Andrea!
谢天谢地
Oh my god!
你吓死我了
You scared the shit out of me.
- 爸爸　-老爸　-嗨
- Papi! - Daddy! - Hey.
宝贝　来这边
Come here, sweetie.
嗨
Hey.
都说了我会回来　没错吧
I told you I'd be back, didn't I?
还能见到你可真好
You are a welcome sight.
我还以为肯定见不到你们了
I thought we had lost you folks for sure.
你们怎么逃出来的
How'd y'all get out of there anyway?
- 有个新来的帮了我们　-新来的
- New guy… he got us out. - New guy?
对　那疯子跑进了城里
Yeah, crazy vato just got into town.
直升机大哥　来跟大家打个招呼
Hey, helicopter boy! Come say hello.
和你一样　那老兄也是警察
The guy's a cop like you.
老天保佑
Oh my god.
爸爸　爸爸
Dad! Dad!
卡尔
Carl.
无所适从
Disoriented.
这最能形容我的感觉
I guess that comes closest.
完全不知所措
Disoriented.
夹杂着恐惧　茫然和迷惑
Fear, confusion… all those things but…
但主要还是无所适从
disoriented comes closest.
语言无法形容
Words can be meager things.
有时候语言是如此苍白
Sometimes they fall short.
我感觉像是被从这个世界
I felt like I'd been ripped out of my life.
隔离了出去
and put somewhere else.
我一度以为自己陷进了
For a while I thought I was trapped.
昏迷中的噩梦里
in some coma dream,
再也醒不过来了
something I might not wake up from ever.
妈妈说你死了
Mom said you died.
她这么想合情合理
She had every reason to believe that.
不要怪她
Don't you ever doubt it.
情况变糟糕的时候
When things started to get really bad,
院方的人和我说
they told me at the hospital that.
要把你们这批患者转移到亚特兰大
they were gonna medevac you and the other patients to Atlanta,
结果却没了下文
and it never happened.
看到亚特兰大这德行我也不奇怪了
Well, I'm not surprised after Atlanta fell.
看来就连医院也被行尸占领了
Yeah. And from the look of that hospital, it got overrun.
一点没错　我好不容易才把大家救出来
Yeah, looks don't deceive. I barely got them out,
知道吗
you know?
我不知道该怎么感激你才好
I can't tell you how grateful I am to you, Shane.
我不知还能说什么
I can't begin to express it.
语言又显得苍白无力了
There go those words falling short again.
得了　区区小事
Paltry things.
爱德　能别随便添柴火吗
Hey, Ed, you want to rethink that log?
太冷了　伙计
It's cold, man.
再冷规矩总不能坏　你说呢
The cold don't change the rules, does it?
火得小些　有点就行了
Keep our fires low, just embers.
- 以免被发现　-我说了　天气太冷
- So we can't be seen from a distance, right? - I said it's cold.
你就不能别多管闲事吗
You should mind your own business for once.
爱德
Hey, Ed…
你非要和我叫板吗
are you sure you want to have this conversation, man?
好吧　把火熄了
Go on. Pull the damn thing out.
快点
Go on!
老天
Christ.
卡萝尔　索菲亚　晚上还好吗
Hey, Carol, Sophia, how are y'all this evening?
- 没事　我们能行　-好
- Fine. We're just fine. - Okay.
- 火堆的事抱歉　-别这么说
- I'm sorry about the fire. - No no no.
不用道歉
No apology needed.
晚上好好休息
Y'all have a good night, okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢合作
I appreciate the cooperation.
你想过怎么和达里尔·迪克森说了吗
Have you given any thought to Daryl Dixon?
他要是知道自己哥哥被抛弃肯定不高兴
He won't be happy to hear his brother was left behind.
我来和他说　是我弄掉的钥匙　我自己担着
I'll tell him. I dropped the key. It's on me.
是我铐的他　所以是我的事
I cuffed him. That makes it mine.
伙计们　这没什么好争的
Guys, it's not a competition.
我不想扯到种族问题
I don't mean to bring race into this,
不过说成白人做的应该好点
but it might sound better coming from a white guy.
一人做事一人当
I did what I did.
我他妈就该离他远点
Hell if I'm gonna hide from him.
- 咱可以骗他　-还是实话实说的好
- We could lie. - Or tell the truth.
莫尔那时都失控了
Merle was out of control.
必须有所行动　不然他会害死我们
Something had to be done or he'd have gotten us killed.
你丈夫必须这么做
Your husband did what was necessary.
莫尔被落下了
And if Merle got left behind,
是他咎由自取
it is nobody's fault but Merle's.
就跟达里尔这么说吗
And that's what we tell Daryl?
我觉得他可不会和你讲道理　你说呢
I don't see a rational discussion to be had from that, do you?
不用我多说吧
Word to the wise…
等他弟弟打猎回来
we're gonna have our hands full.
我们就有的忙活了
when he gets back from his hunt.
我吓坏了　所以先逃了
I was scared and I ran.
- 这点我承认　-我们都吓坏了
- I'm not ashamed of it. - We were all scared.
我们都逃了　你要说什么
We all ran. What's your point?
我把门用链子锁上了
I stopped long enough to chain that door.
楼梯很窄
Staircase is narrow.
也许一次可以
Maybe half a dozen geeks can squeeze against it.
挤下六七只怪物
at any one time.
但这还不足以闯进去
It's not enough to break through that…
门上有链子和挂锁
not that chain, not that padlock.
我要说的是　迪克森还活着
My point… Dixon's alive.
还在那上面　被手铐铐着
and he's still up there, handcuffed on that roof.
是我们的责任
That's on us.
终于找到你了吧
I found you, didn't I?
我爱你　爸爸
I love you, dad.
我也爱你　卡尔
I love you, Carl.
终于找到你们俩了
I found you both.
是啊
Yeah.
我就知道能找到你们
I knew I would.
你有点得瑟了
You're getting cocky now, a little bit.
没有　我真的知道
No. No, I knew.
我回过家里一趟　发现空无一人
Walking into our home, finding an empty house,
- 你们都走了　-对不起
- both of you gone. - I'm so sorry.
我知道你们还活着
I knew you were alive.
怎么知道
How?
相片不见了
The photos were gone,
我们的相册都不见了
all our family albums.
我说过我知道
I told you so.
现在算是得瑟了吧
Now you're getting cocky, huh?
相当得瑟
A lot.
这张是在这里的
It belongs in here.
亲爱的　我真的以为再也见不到你了
Baby, I really thought I would never see you again.
对不起
I'm so sorry…
真的对不起
for everything.
我感觉…
I feel like…
你在医院的时候　我
when you were in the hospital, I just…
我真的很回到过去
I wanted to take it all back…
就算是我们以前争吵的日子
the anger and the bad times.
只要能弥补那些过错
But the mistakes…
我们还有机会
Maybe we got a second chance.
不是每个人都有这种机会
Not many people get that.
我到处找都没找到
I wondered where that went.
想要回去吗
Do you want it back?
当然
Of course.
他不会醒的
He won't wake up.
- 早　-早
- Morning. - Morning.
- Hey. - Hi.
- 早　-早
- Morning. - Morning.
衣服还没干
They're still a little damp.
有太阳的话马上就干了
The sun'll have'em dry in no time.
你把我的衣服也洗了吗
You washed my clothes?
嗯　我们尽力而为
Well, best we could.
在洗衣板上洗
Scrubbing on a washboard.
不如家里的旧洗衣机洗得干净
ain't half as good as my old Maytag back home.
你真好　谢谢
That's very kind. Thank you.
你看他们
Look at'em.
恶心的秃鹫
Vultures.
继续啊　拆干净吧
Yeah, go on, strip it clean.
发电机需要燃料
Generators need every drop of fuel they can get.
不然就发动不了车了　对不住了　格伦
Got no power without it. Sorry, Glenn.
还以为能再飙上几天呢
Thought I'd get to drive it at least a few more days.
也许哪天还能再偷一辆来
Maybe we'll get to steal another one someday.
警长早啊
Morning, officer.
睡得香吗
You sleep okay?
很久没睡这么香了
Better than in a long time.
我不想吵醒你
Well, I didn't want to wake you.
我想让你多睡会儿
I figured you could use it.
- 怎么了　-我在想
- God. What? - I've been thinking.
被落下的那个人
about the man we left behind.
你不是认真的吧
You're not serious.
水来了
Water's here, y'all.
提醒你们　烧开了再用
Just a reminder to boil before use.
你是在问我意见还是通知我
Are you asking me or telling me?
- 问你意见　-我觉得你疯了
- Asking. - Well, I think it's crazy.
我觉得这样实在是太蠢了
I think it is just the stupidest way to break your…
- 妈妈　-卡尔
- Mom! - Carl?
在那边
It's over there!
- 爸爸　-宝贝
- Dad! - Baby!
- 妈妈　妈咪　-瑞克　给
- Mama! Mommy! - Rick!
- 卡尔　-过来孩子们　快过来
- Carl! - Over here, boy! Come on, come on!
卡尔　宝贝
Carl! Baby!
- 妈妈　-你没事吧　过来　过来
- Mom! - You're okay! I've got him. I've got him.
- 有没有被咬被抓伤　-没有　我没事
- Nothing bit you? Nothing scratched you? - No, I'm okay.
头一回在这里碰上
It's the first one we've had up here.
他们从没跑这么远到山上来
They never come this far up the mountain.
城里没吃的了　所以跑上山了
Well, they're running out of food in the city, that's what.
- 我靠　-狗娘养的
- Oh, Jesus. - Son of a bitch.
那是我打到的鹿
That's my deer!
瞧瞧　都让这个
Look at it. All gnawed on by this…
脏兮兮的　染了病的
filthy, disease-bearing,
没娘养的杂种糟蹋了
motherless poxy bastard!
算了　孩子　这没用
Calm down, son. That's not helping.
你知道个屁　老不死的
What do you know about it, old man?
戴着你这傻逼帽子回你的“金池塘”去吧
You take this stupid hat and go back to "On Golden Pond"?
老子大老远追着这只鹿
I've been tracking this deer for miles.
想把它带回营地
Gonna drag it back to camp,
给大伙上点鹿肉吃
cook us up some venison.
你们觉得怎样　把咬掉的这部分
What do you think? Do you think we can cut around.
割掉怎么样
this chewed up part right here?
我才不冒那个险
I would not risk that.
真他妈糟蹋了
That's a damn shame.
我猎了些松鼠　十来只
I got some squirrel… about a dozen or so.
这能吃吧
That'll have to do.
天啊
Oh god.
你们这帮人　有没有搞错
Come on, people. What the hell?
要命中脑袋才行
It's gotta be the brain.
你们连这都不懂吗
Don't y'all know nothing?
莫尔
Merle!
莫尔　你他妈的给我滚出来
Merle! Get your ugly ass out here!
我猎了些松鼠
I got us some squirrel!
过来一起煮
Let's stew 'em up.
达里尔　等一下　我有话跟你说
Daryl, just slow up a bit. I need to talk to you.
说什么
About what?
莫尔
About Merle.
在亚特兰大出了些问题
There was a… there was a problem in Atlanta.
他死了吗
He dead?
还不确定
We're not sure.
他是死是活你怎会不知道
He either is or he ain't!
我只是不能确定
No easy way to say this, so I'll just say it.
- 你是谁　-瑞克·格兰姆斯
- Who are you?　- Rick Grimes.
瑞克·格兰姆斯　你有什么话要说
Rick Grimes, you got something you want to tell me?
你哥哥对我们造成了威胁
Your brother was a danger to us all,
所以我把他铐在屋顶的一条金属管上
so I handcuffed him on a roof, hooked him to a piece of metal.
他还在那儿
He's still there.
慢着　让我好好消化一下
Hold on. Let me process this.
你是说你把我哥铐在屋顶上
You're saying you handcuffed my brother to a roof.
还把他丢在那里
And you left him there?!
是的
Yeah.
小心刀子
Watch the knife!
好了
Okay. Okay.
- 快放开我　-我看还是不要了
- You'd best let me go!　- Nah, I think it's better if I don't.
锁喉不合法
Chokehold's illegal.
你去投诉吧
You can file a complaint.
得了　伙计　我们能耗上一整天
Come on, man. We'll keep this up all day.
我想和你冷静下来谈谈这事
I'd like to have a calm discussion on this topic.
你能做到吗
Do you think we can manage that?
我那么做并不是一时兴起
What I did was not on a whim.
你哥哥和其他人相处不太好
Your brother does not work and play well with others.
那不是瑞克的错　我拿着钥匙
It's not Rick's fault. I had the key.
- 结果掉了　-你不能捡起来吗
- I dropped it.　- You couldn't pick it up?
我把它掉进下水道了
Well, I dropped it in a drain.
别以为这能让我好受点
If it's supposed to make me feel better, it don't.
那不如听听这个
Well, maybe this will.
我把屋顶的门用锁链锁上了
Look, I chained the door to the roof…
所以那些行尸抓不到他
so the geeks couldn't get at him…
- 门上有挂锁　-这该有点用吧
- With a padlock.　- It's gotta count for something.
你们都给我去死
Hell with all y'all!
告诉我他在哪里
Just tell me where he is.
我去救他出来
so's I can go get him.
他会带你去
He'll show you.
不是吗
Isn't that right?
我要回去
I'm going back.
就这样吗
So that's it, huh?
你准备这么走掉
You're just gonna walk off?
丢下所有人不管吗
Just to hell with everybody else?
我不会丢下所有人不管
I'm not saying to hell with anybody…
至少不会丢下你和洛莉
Not you Shane; Lori least of all.
跟她说吧
Tell her that.
她懂的
She knows.
听着　我
Well, look, I…
我不懂　瑞克　你可以
I don't, okay, Rick? So could you just…
你可以告诉我吗
Could you throw me a bone here, man?
告诉我为什么这么做
Could you just tell me why?
为什么你要为莫尔·迪克森这种人渣冒这险
Why would you risk your life for a douche bag like Merle Dixon?
- 说话小心点　-我很小心了
- Hey, choose your words more carefully.　- No, I did.
人渣算客气的了　莫尔·迪克森
Douche bag's what I meant. Merle Dixon…
即使你渴死他也不会给你水喝
The guy wouldn't give you a glass of water if you were dying of thirst.
他这人怎么样与我无关
What he would or wouldn't do doesn't interest me.
我可不会让一个人渴死
I can't let a man die of thirst… me.
就这么被活活晒死
Thirst and exposure.
我们把他扔在那　就像掉进陷阱的动物
We left him like an animal caught in a trap.
谁都不能这样死　更别说一个活生生的人了
That's no way for anything to die, let alone a human being.
就你和达里尔俩　这就是你们的计划吗
So you and Daryl, that's your big plan?
不是吧
Oh, come on.
你认得路　你之前去过那儿
You know the way. You've been there before…
进进出出都不是问题　你自己说的
In and out, no problem. You said so yourself.
我知道这很不公平
It's not fair of me to ask… I know that…
但和你在一起我更有安全感
But I'd feel a lot better with you along.
我想她也会这么想
I know she would too.
很好　你三个人一起去冒险
That's just great. Now you're gonna risk three men, huh?
四个
Four.
这么多人　我真是受宠若惊
My day just gets better and better, don't it?
你看还有别人主动站出来
You see anybody else here stepping up.
救你那混账老哥么
to save your brother's cracker ass?
- 那你干嘛去　-你不会懂的
- Why you?　- You wouldn't even begin to understand.
- 我们不是一类人　-那就四个人吧
- You don't speak my language. - That's four.
不只是四个人
It's not just four.
你让我们所有人都处于危险之中
You're putting every single one of us at risk.
你也知道　瑞克　你看到那行尸
Just know that, Rick. Come on, you saw that walker.
就在这儿　就出现在营地里
It was here. It was in camp.
他们开始在城市外行动了
They're moving out of the cities.
他们要来了　我们需要所有有生力量
They come back, we need every able body we've got.
我们要留在这里保护营地
We need 'em here. We need 'em to protect camp.
在我看来　这里更需要的
It seems to me what you really need most here.
- 是更多的枪　-没错　枪
- are more guns.　- Right, the guns.
- 等等　什么枪　-六支猎枪
- Wait. What guns? - Six shotguns,
两支强火力步枪　还有十来支手枪
two high-powered rifles, over a dozen handguns.
走之前　我把警局里的仓库搜了个遍
I cleaned out the cage back at the station before I left.
在亚特兰大被困住时　我把那袋子掉了
I dropped the bag in Atlanta when I got swarmed.
就在大街上　我们得拿回来
It's just sitting there on the street, waiting to be picked up.
- 多少弹药　-各式各样一共七百发
- Ammo?　- 700 rounds, assorted.
你历经艰辛找到我们
You went through hell to find us.
现在又要转身离开吗
You just got here and you're gonna turn around and leave?
爸爸　我不想你去
Dad, I don't want you to go.
别管那些枪了　肖恩是对的
To hell with the guns. Shane is right.
莫尔·迪克森
Merle Dixon?
就算加上那些枪　也不值得我们去冒险
He's not worth one of your lives, even with guns thrown in.
告诉我为什么
Tell me. Make me understand.
我遇到一个男人和他的孩子　我欠他们人情
I owe a debt to a man I met and his little boy.
洛莉　要不是他们收留了我
Lori, if they hadn't taken me in,
我早就死了
I'd have died.
如果没有他们　我们不可能重逢
It's because of them that I made it back to you at all.
他们说会跟着我到亚特兰大
They said they'd follow me to Atlanta.
如果我不提醒他　他们会重蹈我的覆辙
They'll walk into the same trap I did if I don't warn him.
为什么你联系不上他们
What's stopping you?
对讲机落在那个袋子里了
The walkie-talkie, the one in the bag I dropped.
他手里也有一个
He's got the other one.
我们本来说好他们快到时再联系
Our plan was to connect when they got closer.
- 是我们的对讲机吗　-对
- These are our walkies? - Yeah.
那就用这个民用电台不行吗
So use the C.B… What's wrong with that?
民用电台是可以
The C.B.'s fine.
但那些垃圾对讲机
It's the walkies that suck to crap…
都是七十年代的了　不适用于其它频宽
date back to the '70s, don't match any other bandwidth…
连我们车里的天线都不行
not even the scanners in our cars.
我需要那个袋子
I need that bag.
好吗
Okay?
好吧
All right.
听说你有断线钳
Rumor is you have bolt cutters.
- 可能吧　-到了屋顶上
- Maybe. - Yeah, we get to that roof, though,
我们得弄断锁链和手铐
we'll need to cut that chain and the handcuffs.
我向来不喜欢外借工具
I never like lending tools.
上次有人借
The last time I did…
对　说的就是你
and yes, I am talking about you…
这么说吧　被丢在那里的
let's just say your bag of guns.
不只是你那袋枪而已
wasn't the only bag that was dropped.
我的工具也被丢下了　在莫尔那
My tools got left behind with Merle.
我们会把你的工具也带回来
We'll bring your tools back too.
就当断线钳是投资好了
Think of the bolt cutters as an investment.
更像赌博才是
Sounds like more of a gamble.
- 那我有什么好处　-想要什么好处
- What do I get in return? - What do you want?
要你们带回来的一杆枪怎么样
How about one of those guns you bring back?
- 由我挑　-成交
- My pick. - Done.
戴尔　不如…
Dale, let's…
让这交易多点甜头
sweeten the deal a bit.
你的那辆小货车
Now that cube van of yours…
车怎么了
What about it?
房车的水箱软管被击中了
The R.V.'s radiator hose is shot.
如果我们要转移或者跑远路
That's a problem if we.
就会出问题
need to get somewhere and wanna get very far.
用你小货车上的软管正好合适
And the hose on that van is just about a perfect match…
总之　我可以让它完全合适
Well, enough that I can make it fit.
这么说吧　等我们回来
I'll tell you what… we get back,
你要把那车拆成废铁我都没意见
you can strip that van down to the bare metal.
- 快点　出发吧　-谢谢你
- Come on, let's go! - Thank you.
瑞克　蟒蛇转轮里还有子弹吗
Hey, Rick, got any rounds in the Python?
没有
No.
上次咱俩射击比赛的时候
Last time we were on the gun range,
我最后肯定拿了一些你的松头子弹
I'm sure I wound up with a few loose rounds of yours.
你和那个袋子　就像个百宝箱
You and that bag… like the bottom of an old lady's purse.
你这么做　我很不爽　伙计
I hate that you're doing this, man.
愚蠢而鲁莽
I think that it's foolish and reckless.
但如果你执意要去　好歹带上子弹
But if you're gonna go, you're taking bullets.
我不太想在城里开枪
I'm not sure I'd want to fire a shot in the city,
- 前车之鉴　-随你的便
- Not after what happened last time. - That's up to you.
好吧
Well…
四个人　四发子弹
Four men, four rounds.
太巧了　不是吗
What are the odds, huh?
我们只能希望…
Well, let's just hope that…
四是你的幸运数字吧
let's just hope four is your lucky number, okay?
- 谢谢　-不客气
- Thank you. - All right.
我觉得他们会没事
You know, I bet they'll be just fine.
我不担心
I'm not worried.
你担心吗
Are you?
嗯　有一点
Yeah, a little.
不用担心
Don't be.
- 为什么　-你想啊　妈妈
- Why? - Think about it, mom.
他经历了这么多事
Everything that's happened to him so far…
却还是安然无恙
nothing's killed him yet.
他最好没事
He'd better be okay.
我就这一句话
It's my only word on the matter.
告诉过你了　行尸们无法接近他
I told you the geeks can't get at him.
只有我们能打开那扇门
The only thing that's gonna get through that door is us.
从这开始步行吧
We walk from here.
戴尔
Dale.
- 看到卡尔了吗　-肖恩带他去采石场了
- Have you seen Carl? - Shane took him down to the quarry.
还大言不惭地说要抓一堆青蛙呢
There was some mighty bold talk about catching frogs.
我什么都捉不到
I'm not getting anything.
对啊
Yeah.
它们都狡猾地躲在水下了
Being all wily, staying submerged.
那帮小废物肯定发现情况不妙了
Little suckers, they know something's up.
肯定是这样
That's what's going on.
只好用老办法解决了
Just going to have to do this the old-fashioned way.
听着　小伙子
All right, little man, look.
你才是关键
You are the… you are the key in all this, okay?
我只是负责去追它们中的一只
All I'm gonna do is I'm gonna go after one of them,
把其它的都吓跑
All right, scare the rest of them off.
它们会四处逃窜　我把它们都往你那边赶
They're all gonna scatter. I'm gonna drive 'em your way.
- 好吧　-你就负责捉住每个
- All right. - What you need to do is you need to round up.
打你眼皮底下溜过的小坏蛋　懂了吗
every bad boy you see, all right? Are you with me?
- 懂了　-懂了就好　凶一点我看看
- Yeah. Yeah. - Hells yeah. Give me your mean face.
好了长官　准备好了吗
Yes sir. Are you ready?
- 准备好了　-准备好了吗　开始吧
- Yeah! - Are you ready? Here we go, boy.
好了　小伙子　它们朝你的方向去了
All right, little man, they're coming your way.
朝你那去了　快　抓住它们
They're coming your wa go on, get 'em, get 'em.
朝你那去了　快点
They're coming your way, come on.
捉住这些小青蛙　捉住这些小青蛙
Catch them frogs. Catch them frogs.
来了来了　小伙子
They're coming, little man!
快抓　把网放那边抓住它们
Get 'em! Get that net in there and get 'em!
我开始置疑这里的劳动分工问题了
I'm beginning to question the division of labor here.
它们来了　小伙子
They're coming, little man!
快用网网住它们　快　抓住它们
Get 'em! Get that net in there and get 'em!
坏小子　有啥收获　都抓到啥啦
What have you got, bad boy? What do you got? What do you got?
屁也没
Dirt.
可怜的娃　算了　咱继续努力
Oh boy. All right, we've got to start over.
加油吧　先找水桶
Come on, let's find this bucket.
有人能解释一下为什么女人
Can someone explain to me how the.
就得跟菲佣似的尽伺候男人
women wound up doing all the Hattie Mcdaniel work?
世界末日到了　你不知道吗
The world ended. Didn't you get the memo?
世道就是如此　认了吧
It's just the way it is.
- 先救莫尔还是先取枪　-先救莫尔
- Merle first or guns? - Merle!
- 没的商量　-我们得计划一下
- We ain't even having this conversation. - We are.
这里你比较熟悉　由你决定
You know the geography. It's your call.
莫尔离这最近
Merle's closest.
取枪的话　我们得原路折回
The guns would mean doubling back.
先救莫尔
Merle first.
我真想念我的洗衣机
I do miss my Maytag.
我想念我的奔驰和卫星导航系统
I miss my Benz, my sat nav.
我想念我那台
I miss my coffeemaker.
带有双向滴漏过滤器
with that dual-drip filter.
以及内置研磨器的咖啡机
and built-in grinder, honey.
我想我的电脑…
My computer…
还有发短信
And texting.
我想念我的按摩棒
I miss my vibrator.
天呐
Oh my god!
我也想
Me too.
你们笑什么呢
What's so funny?
分享个人英勇事迹而已　爱德
Just swapping war stories, Ed.
对吧
Yeah.
有事吗　爱德
Problem, Ed?
与你无关
Nothin' that concerns you.
专心洗你的衣服　废话少说
And you ought to focus on your work.
这可不是什么喜剧俱乐部
This ain't no comedy club.
卡尔
Hey, Carl.
我不是跟你说过别离开戴尔的视线吗
What did I tell you about not leaving Dale's sight?
可肖恩说我们要一起抓青蛙　还记得吗
But Shane said we could catch frogs, remember?
肖恩说什么不打紧　听我的就是了
It doesn't matter what Shane says. It matters what I say.
走吧　回营地去
Go on back to camp.
我就跟在你后面
I'll be right behind you.
恕我直言
I've got to tell you,
我认为你不该拿他出气
I do not think you should be taking this out on him.
不用你来告诉我怎么做
You don't tell me what to do.
你已经没这个权利了
You lost that privilege.
洛莉　等一下好吗
Lori, could you just wait up a second?
我们该谈谈　我们都没有机会…
I think we should talk. We haven't had a chance…
不了　不用谈了
No. No no.
我们已经结束了　要谈跟青蛙谈去
That's over too. You can tell that to the frogs.
该死　洛莉
Damn it, Lori.
我不知道你是如何看待这事
Look, I don't know how it appears to you.
或者你是怎么想的…
or what you think…
我是如何看的　抱歉
How it appears to me? I'm sorry.
难道我说的还不够清楚吗　我再说一遍
Is there a gray area here? Let me dispel it.
你离我远点　离我儿子远点
You stay away from me. You stay away from my son.
别看着他　别跟他说话
You don't look at him. You don't talk to him.
从现在开始　禁止与我们一家人接触
From now on, my family is off-limits to you.
洛莉　这不公平
Lori, I don't think that's fair.
- 肖恩　闭嘴　给我闭嘴　-我认为…
- Shane, shut up. Don't! - I don't think that…
我老公回来了　他还活着
My husband is back. He is alive.
他是我最好的兄弟
He's my best friend.
你觉得我反而不高兴吗
Do you think I'm not happy about that?
你怎么敢这样　你为什么做这种事
How dare you? Why would you be?
是你告诉我他已经死了
You are the one that told me that he died.
你个狗杂种
You son of a bitch.
操　你个恶心巴拉的小丑
Damn. You are one ugly skank.
爱德　这么说吧
Ed, tell you what…
既然你不乐意我们洗你的衣服
You don't like how your laundry is done,
我们倒是很乐意你自个儿洗　接着
you are welcome to pitch in and do it yourself. Here.
美女　这不是我该干的活
Ain't my job, missy.
安德莉亚　别这样
Andrea, don't.
那你干什么活　爱德
What is your job, Ed?
死坐着抽烟吗
Sitting on your ass smoking cigarettes?
总比听一个自作聪明的婊子
Well, it sure as hell ain't listening.
说教来的强
to some uppity smart-mouthed bitch.
明白吗　我们走
Tell you what… come on. Let's go.
我认为她没必要跟着你走　爱德
I don't think she needs to go anywhere with you, Ed.
干你屁事　快点
And I say it's none of your business. Come on now.
- 你听到了　-卡萝尔
- You heard me. - Carol.
安德莉亚　放心　没事的
Andrea, please. It doesn't matter.
别以为自己读过大学
Hey, don't think I won't knock you on your ass.
我就不会揍你　你就一逼货
just 'cause you're some college-educated cooze,
听明白了吗
All right?
你要么现在跟我走　要不有你后悔的
Now you come on now or you gonna regret it later.
不然她会带着新伤出现吗　爱德
So she can show up with fresh bruises later, Ed?
是呀　我们亲眼见过
Yeah, we've seen them.
别多管闲事　快点
Stay out of this. Now come on!
你知道吗　这跟你们屁点关系也没
You know what? This ain't none of y'all's business.
你们也不想惹怒一头公牛吧
You don't want to keep prodding the bull here, okay?
话我已经说够了　赶紧走
Now I am done talking. Come on.
不　别走　卡萝尔　你不必…
No no. Carol, you don't have…
你再多舌试试用　告诉你
You don't tell me what! I tell you what!
- 你别以为你能怎么着　-放开她
- You think you can… - Get off her!
- 过来　过来　-放开她
- Come here! Come here! - Get off her!
- 放开她　放开她　-放开我
- Get off her! Get off her! - Get off me!
爱德
Ed?
- 没事的　没事　-不要
- It's okay. It's okay. - No!
- 没事的　-不要
- It's okay. - No!
肖恩　别打了
Shane, stop!
快住手
Just stop!
别打了
Stop it!
- 别打了　-你要是再敢对你的妻子
- Stop! - You put your hands on your wife,
女儿或者这里的任何一个人动手
your little girl or anybody else in this camp.
下次我不会就这么放过你　听到了没
one more time, I will not stop next time. Do you hear me?
- 你听到了没　-听到了
- Do you hear me?! - Yes.
- 我会打死你　爱德　-爱德
- I'll beat you to death, Ed. - Ed!
老天爷
Oh god!
不要
No.
天哪
God!
爱德　对不起
Ed, I'm sorry.
天哪　爱德　都是我的错
Oh my god. Ed, I'm sorry.
对不起　爱德
I'm so sorry, Ed.
爱德　对不起
Ed, I'm sorry.
对不起　爱德
I'm sorry, Ed.
莫尔　莫尔
Merle! Merle!
不　不
No! No!
不
No!
天呐　不
No! No!